blueclaw.co.uk 2019-05-05

# Privacy Policy - Blueclaw

**Blueclaw Media Ltd. Privacy and Data Policy 2018**

This Privacy Policy governs the way Blueclaw Media Ltd gathers, uses, maintains and discloses information collected from website users, and how we manage our marketing communications.  
This privacy policy applies to the Site and all services and products provided by Blueclaw.

The terms ‘we’, ‘us’ or ‘Blueclaw’ each reference Blueclaw Media Ltd.

We are registered in England with **company number 05985341**  
Blueclaw are registered with the Information Commissioner’s Office with **registration number ZA208714**

 **Right to be informed**  
We take our data protection obligations seriously. You have a right to be informed about how your data will be used. If you would like to speak to us about any matter concerning data protection and the use of your data, please get in touch with us in any of the following ways:

 **By email:** contact@blueclaw.co.uk  
 **By phone:** 0113 234 3300  
 **Through our website** : https://www.blueclaw.co.uk  
 **By post:**

Jenny Clawson  
Blueclaw  
46 The Calls  
Leeds  
LS2 7EY

 **About this privacy policy**  
This policy sets out how we will use and share the information that you give us. This privacy policy relates to personal data collected by us via:

• Visiting our office  
• Using our website  
• Enquiring about or using our services  
• Supplying products or services to us  
• Email communication  
• Telephone calls  
• Postal communications  
• Social media engagement  
• Enquiring about or using our services  
• Supplying products or services to us  
• Industry events including seminars, networking events, conferences and exhibitions

 **Data we may process**

Blueclaw may collect and process the following categories of data:

• Contact details including first name, last name and email  
• Company data  
• Information generated by visiting our website or engaging with us on social media:  
• IP addresses, social usernames  
• Non-personal identification information, including browser, device type and the ways in which Users visit our Site and related information.

 **Legitimate Business Interests and GDPR**

Recital 47 of the GDPR allows for the processing of personal information for our legitimate business interests in terms of direct marketing. “Legitimate Interests” means the interests of our company in conducting and managing our business to enable us to offer digital marketing services.

When we process personal information based on legitimate interests, we make sure to consider and balance any potential impact on you (both positive and negative), and your rights under data protection laws.

We may process your data or communicate with you to:

• Deliver a contract or respond to an enquiry or request  
• Keep you informed of our products, tools and services where we have a legitimate interest to unless you’ve objected to us doing so.  
• Send you marketing and information about our business via email  
• Add it to information that we already hold on you or your organisation

Our legitimate business interests do not automatically override your interests. We will not use your Personal Data for activities where our interests are overridden by the impact on you.

 **Information Sharing**  
We may also share some of your personal data with suppliers providing services to us to help us run our business  
We require third parties to respect the security of your data and to treat it in accordance with the law. We will share your personal information with third parties where required by law.

 **Retention of Personal Information**

We will only retain your personal information for as long as necessary to fulfil the purposes we collected it for, including for the purposes of satisfying any legal, accounting or reporting requirements.

To determine the appropriate retention period for personal data, we consider the amount, nature, and sensitivity of the personal data, the potential risk of harm from unauthorised use or disclosure of your personal data, the purposes for which we process your personal data and whether we can achieve those purposes through other means, and the applicable legal requirements.

In some circumstances, we may anonymise your personal information so that it can no longer be associated with you, in which case we may use such information without further notice to you.  
When the purposes for which we have collected the data for have ended we will retain and securely destroy your personal information in accordance with applicable laws and regulations.  
You have the right to:  
• Obtain access to your personal information  
• Withdraw consent  
• Object to direct marketing  
• Ask us to correct any errors or delete the information we hold  
• Object or restrict our processing of your information  
• Request that we port your personal information

 **Cookies**

Our Site may use “cookies” for the purpose of optimising user experience and messaging. User’s web browser places cookies on their computer and sometimes to track information about them. Each User may set their web browser to refuse cookies, or to create a notification when cookies are being passed on. If they do so, note that some parts of the Site may not function as intended.

 **International Transfer of Data**  
Blueclaw may send your data outside the European Economic Area (the European Economic Area being the European Union and Iceland, Liechtenstein and Norway, also referred to as the “EEA. Where your personal data are transferred or accessed outside of the EEA, we require that appropriate safeguards are in place.

 **Changes**  
We may change the terms of this privacy policy from time to time. Any changes will be posted on this page.  
This document was last updated on **May 25, 2018**
